Blue Moon
You saw me standing alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love of my own
Blue moon
You knew just what I was there for
You heard me saying a prayer for
Someone I really could care for
And then there suddenly appeared before me
The only one my arms will ever hold
I heard somebody whisper please adore me
And when I looked
the moon had turned to gold
Blue moon
Now I'm no longer alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love of my own
And then there suddenly appeared before me
The only one my arms will ever hold
I heard somebody whisper please adore me
And when I looked
the moon had turned to gold
Blue moon
Now I'm no longer alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love of my own
Blue moon
That's East Proctor,
and all about here are the moors.
I go this way.
Thanks for the ride, sir.
You have lovely sheep.
Boys, keep off the moors.
Stick to the roads, and the best of luck.
Thanks again. I'm gonna miss you.
Bye, girls.
- You cold?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- Jack!
- David.
- You're not having a good time, are you?
Oh, I don't know. I mean, look around.
Isn't this a fun place?
- Well, I like it here.
- Right.
- Northern England first, Italy later.
- I mean, we've got three months.
- Right.
Those sheep shit on my pack.
You think she'll meet me in Rome?
I think Debbie Klein's a mediocre person
with a good body.
There's nothing mediocre about
Debbie Klein's body.
She's a jerk.
You're talking about the woman I love.
I'm talking about a girl you wanna fuck.
So give me a break.
All right. Well, I have to make love to her.
It's really very simple. She has no choice.
It just fascinates me how much energy
you spend on somebody so dull.
There's nothing dull about that body.
We've known Debbie, what,
since the eighth grade?
How many years of foreplay is that?
She says she likes me too much.
What are you worried about
Debbie Klein for, anyway?
There are gonna be plenty of girls
on this trip.
We're off to a great start.
- Say, "Knock, knock."
- Knock, knock.
- Who's there?
- Who?
- Don't you get it?
- What?
You don't get that joke?
All right, I'll try another.
- Say, "Knock, knock."
- What?
- Who's there?
- No. No, no, no. You say, "Knock, knock."
- Knock, knock.
- Who's there?
- Who?
No. You don't...
You're right. It is a pub.
Okay, what do you say,
we go in for a little food, drink, rest?
"The Slaughtered Lamb"?
That's kind of strange.
- Where's the lamb?
- It's probably inside getting cold. Come on.
No, really.
What kind of ad is that for a pub?
I don't know. Would you rather the Hilton?
All right, but whatever happens,
- it's your fault.
- It's my fault.
- Right.
- All right. Come on.
Hello.
Hi. Nice to see you.
It's very cold outside. May we come in?
- Yes. Do you have any hot soup?
- No.
- Do you have any coffee, then?
Do you have any hot chocolate?
We have spirits and beers. If it's something
hot that you want, you can have tea.
- Then you have tea?
- No.
- Oh.
- But I can make some for you, if you like.
- Oh, yes, please.
- Nice-looking group.
- Hey, listen, at least it's warm in here.
Look at that.
- Yeah, what about it?
- It's a five-pointed star.
Maybe the owners are from Texas.
- Remember the Alamo.
- I beg your pardon?
- Oh, he was just joking.
- Joking?
I remember The Alamo. I saw it once
in London, in Leicester Square.
She means in the cinema,
that film with John Wayne.
Oh, yeah, of course.
Checkmate.
Right. With Laurence Harvey.
Everybody dies in it. Very bloody.
Bloody awful, if you ask me.
Here, Gladys, Tom. Did you hear
the one about that rushing...
Let me speak!
- Ask him what the candles are for.
- You ask him.
All right, then. I shan't tell it.
No, no, you've had your chance.
It's a pentangle, a five-pointed star.
It's used in witchcraft.
Lon Chaney, Jr., in Universal Studios,
maintained that's the mark of the Wolf Man.
I see. You want me to ask them if they're
burning candles to ward off monsters.
- Right.
- Wrong.
All right, then! There was this airplane
over the Atlantic on its way to New York,
and it was full of men
from the United Nations.
- Go on, ask him.
- You ask him.
So halfway over the ocean
the engines run low on petrol.
So, they have to lighten the plane.
So they heave out all the baggage,
but it's still too heavy.
So they chuck out all the seats,
Finally, this Frog, he steps up, shouts,
"Vive la France," and leaps out.
- Then an Englishman, he steps up, shouts...
- Hear, hear.
..."God save the Queen,"  and he leaps out.
But the plane is still too heavy.
So the Yank delegate from Texas,
he steps up, shouts,
"Remember the Alamo,"
and chucks out the Mexican!
Remember the Alamo.
Excuse me. What's that star on the wall for?
You made me miss.
I'm sorry.
I've never missed that board before.
Jack, we'd better go.
Are you kidding? I'm starved.
There's no food here.
- Shall we go, Jack?
- Apparently so.
- You can't let them go.
- How much do we owe you?
Nothing, lads. Go. God be with you.
- Thank you.
- Wait!
You just can't let them go.
Go. Stay on the road.
Keep clear of the moors.
- Thank you.
- Beware the moon, lads.
Yeah.
- What the hell was that all about?
- I don't know.
Let's go up the road and see if there's
an inn or something.
"Beware the moon"?
Yeah, I know, Jack, but come on.
I'm freezing.
Where the hell are we going?
Anywhere. I just want to get away
from The Slaughtered Lamb.
Where to now, Kessler? The Duck's Breath?
Okay, look, I'm sorry.
I'm sure we'll find something else.
- Weird fucking place.
- It was, man.
But, boy, they could play darts.
You can't let them go.
Should the world know our business?
- It's murder, then!
- Then murder it is.
It's in God's hands now.
- What do you think was wrong?
- I have no idea.
Maybe that pentangle
was for something supernatural.
Oh, I see.
And they were too embarrassed to talk
about it because they just felt so silly.
- They were ashamed.
- Yeah.
Oh, please, don't rain!
Oh! Of course.
- Oh, David.
- Yes, I'm well aware
of how pleasant the weather is in Rome
at the present time, thank you.
Santa Lucia
- Santa Lucia
It's-a-cold and-a-wet out here!
Perhaps they'll be safe in the rain.
No one brought them here.
No one wanted them here.
- You could have told them.
- Are you daft?
And what do you think they'd say?
They'd think us mad.
Listen.
Do you hear it?
We must go to them.
I heard nothing.
Nor I.
Did you hear that?
- I heard that.
- What was it?
Could be a lot of things.
Yeah?
- A coyote.
- There aren't any coyotes in England.
- The hound of the Baskervilles?
- Pecos Bill?
- Heathcliff.
- Heathcliff didn't howl.
No, but he was on the moors.
It's a full moon.
- "Beware the moon."
"And stick to the road." Oops.
I vote we go back to The Slaughtered Lamb.
Yeah.
Hey, wait a minute. We're lost.
Shit, David. What is that?
- I don't know. Come on.
- "Come on" where?
Anywhere.
I think we should just keep moving.
It's moving.
It's circling us.
Oh, fuck.
- What's the plan?
- Plan?
Let's just keep walking.
That's right. A lovely stroll on the moors.
Tra-la-la-la. Isn't this fun?
It's in front of us.
Do you think it's a dog?
Oh, shit. What is it?
Yeah, it's a sheepdog or something.
Come on. Turn slowly. Let's walk away.
Nice doggie.
Good boy.
- Come on, Jack. Walk away.
- Walking away. Yes.
Here we are walking away.
- Can you see anything?
- No.
- Sounds far away.
- Not far enough. Come on.
- But, Jack.
- What?
- Where are we going?
- I don't know.
- I'll tell you when we get there.
- Okay, 'cause...
You really scared me, you shithead.
You gonna help me up or what?
Jesus! Fuck! Jesus!
Jesus! Fuck! Oh, God! Help! Help!
It's killing me!
Jack.
Jack?
Mr. Kessler?
I'm going to look into your eyes.
Is he all right?
Yes, I should think.
He called out just now.
He's American, you know.
Dr. Hirsch's gonna fetch one of them
embassy fellas to see him.
- His chart says he's from New York.
- Oh, I think he's a Jew.
- What makes you say that?
- I've had a look.
Really, Susan, that wasn't very proper.
Besides, it's common practice now.
Nurse Gallagher, Nurse Price is quite right.
Dr. Hirsch, Mr. Kessler called out just now.
Nurse Gallagher, surely you perform
some function here at the hospital?
- Yes, Doctor.
- Then get on with it.
Yes, Doctor.
Can I be of service, Nurse Price?
- Dr. Hirsch?
- Go about your duties.
Yes, Doctor.
- Oh, Nurse Price.
- Yes, Doctor?
- What exactly did he call out?
- He said, "Jack."
That would be Jack Goodman,
the boy who was killed.
What happened to them?
The police report said
they were attacked by an escaped lunatic.
Must have been a very powerful man.
Although I don't see
that it's any concern of yours, Nurse Price.
No, sir. Of course, sir.
Good day, Doctor.
Hello, David.
I'm Dr. Hirsch.
This is a countryman of yours, Mr. Collins.
- Where am I?
- You're in a hospital in London.
London?
Where's Jack?
David, I'd like you to prepare yourself.
Your friend is dead.
What?
Shit.
Jack is dead?
Hi. I'm Mr. Collins of the American Embassy
here in Grosvenor Square.
Both Mr. Goodman's parents and your
parents have been notified of your injuries
and everything's in order.
Who are you people?
What's going on here? Where's Jack?
Get your hands off me.
- Let go of me. I wanna see Jack!
- Nurse!
- I wanna see Jack.
- Mr. Kessler!
I appreciate
how upsetting this must be for you.
Please, Mr. Kessler!
Twenty milligrams Seconal IV, please.
I appreciate how upset you are,
but this is no reason for hysterics.
Mr. Kessler?
Mr. Kessler, try not to excite yourself.
I shall come back and check on your
progress and send a report to your parents.
The police have requested to interview you,
and I have given them permission to do so.
Thank you very much, Mr. Collins.
He'll rest now.
I'm sure everything will be fine
once he's adjusted.
He's had quite a shock.
These dumb-ass kids. They never appreciate
anything you do for them.
How long have I been here?
You've been unconscious
since you were brought in three weeks ago.
Three weeks?
You've suffered some cuts and bruises.
Lost a little blood. Nothing serious.
Black and blue for a while.
You'll have some dueling scars to boast of.
That lunatic must have been
a very fierce fellow.
They say a madman has the strength of 10.
Lunatic?
We've given you a strong sedative.
Rest now.
Nurse Price will see to all your needs.
You rest.
- It wasn't a lunatic.
- I beg your pardon?
- It was an animal.
- What?
A wolf.
Did he say a wolf?
Yes, I believe he did.
Oh, I'm sure I shall.
If I survived Rommel,
I'm sure I can survive another excruciating
evening with Roger Matheson.
Be a good girl. Bye, now.
Yes?
Inspector Villiers and Sergeant McManus
are here to see you, Doctor.
Send them in.
- Dr. Hirsch.
- Come in. Come in. Please sit down.
- Some tea?
- No, thank you.
I'd like some tea, please.
Maybe not. No, thanks. Maybe later.
- No problem.
- No, thank you, Doctor.
Well, then, what can I do for Scotland Yard?
We understand the Kessler boy
has regained consciousness.
Sorry. Sorry.
Has Mr. Kessler said anything
regarding the attack on the moors?
Excuse me. Yes?
- Roger Matheson, Doctor.
- I'm not here.
- He's on the telephone.
- Tell him I'm out.
Tell him I've passed away,
an old war wound.
Just tell him I'm dead! No more calls.
I'm sorry if I conflict with your report,
Inspector,
but Jack and I were not attacked by a man!
- So you've said.
- He may have a point, sir.
Two strong boys would be able to defend
themselves against one man.
Sergeant McManus,
are you suggesting that David and Jack
were in fact attacked by some animal
and that the officialdom of East Proctor
has conspired to keep it a secret?
We have an autopsy report on the murderer,
who was shot in the act by the local police.
We have two witnesses to the crime.
You'll forgive me, Mr. Kessler,
if I consider your testimony
as coming from someone
who has gone through a terrible shock.
Inspector, the boy seems all right
to me, and...
And what, Sergeant?
- And I don't rightly know, sir.
- That is precisely my point.
David, as far as we're concerned,
the matter is now closed.
We will trouble you no further.
Good day. Doctor.
- There were witnesses?
- So they said.
How could there have been witnesses?
It was so dark.
We were running, and I fell,
and Jack went to help me up,
and this thing came from nowhere.
I don't know what they're talking about.
In time, I'm sure it'll all come back to you.
Doctor, my memory is fine.
It's my sanity I'm beginning to worry about.
- Hello, Benjamin.
- No.
- No what?
Well, all right, then, be like that. Here.
Swallow this.
Want some water?
- Feeling better?
- No!
What a lot of lovely comics you've got.
- Do you like them?
- No.
Right.
How's the patient in 21?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- How did he look?
- What do you mean how did he look?
- Does he seem depressed?
Do you think he'll eat his food?
I'm an orderly, not a bleeding psychiatrist.
I push things around.
- What happens to them, I don't know.
- Thank you.
- Mr. Kessler.
- Yes?
You haven't eaten your lunch.
Well, I'm not very hungry, thank you.
- I'm afraid you have to eat something.
- What?
You have to eat something.
No, really, thanks, I'm not hungry.
You put me in an awkward position,
Mr. Kessler.
- How did I do that?
- You're to take these after you've eaten.
What sort of nurse would I be if I failed in
so simple a task as handing out some pills?
You can leave the pills.
I'll take them later.
Sorry.
- Oh, come on, Nurse Price.
- You can call me Alex.
Come on, Alex.
Shall I be forced to feed you, Mr. Kessler?
You can call me David.
Shall I be forced to feed you, David?
You know, this is absurd.
I'm not hungry. I don't want any food.
Right.
- Let's try a little harder, shall we?
- Would you give me a break?
Will I have to take such drastic action
again, David?
You've never had bad dreams before?
Sure, as a kid, but never so real.
Never so weird.
Did you get a good look at the man
who attacked you?
Doctor, I told you. It wasn't a man.
It was an animal. A big wolf or something.
A rabid dog.
Let's have a look, shall we?
Look, Dr. Hirsch, I know I was traumatized,
but Jack was torn apart.
I saw him. A man can't do that
to someone with his bare hands.
You'd be surprised
what horrors a man is capable of.
- Did you see Jack?
- No.
In fact, your wounds had been cleaned
and dressed before you arrived here.
Did you talk to the police in East Proctor?
Did the cops go to The Slaughtered Lamb?
I really don't know.
Then why the hell are you so quick
to disbelieve me?
- You think I'm crazy.
- David, please. The police are satisfied,
and I'm certain if there were a monster
roaming around Northern England,
we'd have seen it on the telly.
Now you'll be leaving this hospital in
three or four days.
Please, remain sane.
At least until
you're no longer our responsibility.
Dr. Hirsch.
I'd rather not be by myself.
I'll send someone in to keep you company.
You're a very beautiful girl.
I thought you were asleep.
I was.
- Shall I read to you?
- Yeah, okay.
A Connecticut Yankee at King Arthur's Court
by Samuel L. Clemens.
This is after the preface
but before chapter one.
"A Word of Explanation."
"It was in Warwick Castle that I came
across the curious stranger
"who I'm going to talk about.
"He attracted me by three things:
his candid simplicity,
"his marvelous familiarity
with ancient armor,
"and the restfulness of his company,
for he did all the talking.
"We fell together, as modest people will,
"in the tail of the herd
that was being shown through,
"and he at once began to say things
which interested me."
- ...number tonight.
- Puppetry is an art form, Piggy.
- You call that violence "art"?
- Well, violence belongs with puppetry.
He is hitting her.
That's Punch and Judy.
They've always been violent.
- Punch and Judy?
- It's good. It's a good, aggressive behavior.
- Better than my act?
- I'm just watching a puppet show right now.
I was going to bite you very badly.
Get the door!
I'll get it.
I've got a song for tonight.
All right, all right. Hold your horses.
All right, already.
Stop!
And now, ladies and gentlemen...
Hello. Have you been up long?
I've just had a nightmare.
Not to worry. I have just the thing.
Alex!
Holy shit.
You're up!
Good morning, and a good day to you.
We have quite a meal here for you,
bacon and eggs,
porridge, orange juice and toast with jam.
Good stuff there. Now you eat it up, and
I'll be back for the dishes when you finish.
Good morning.
Can I have a piece of toast?
Get the fuck out of here, Jack.
Thanks a lot.
No. I can't take this.
Am I asleep now, awake or what?
I realize I don't look so hot, David,
but I thought you'd be glad to see me.
David! You're hurting my feelings.
Hurting your feelings?
Has it occurred to you
that it might be unsettling
to see you rise from the grave to visit me?
Sorry to be upsetting you, David,
but I had to come.
Aren't you supposed to be buried
someplace in New York?
Yeah. Your parents came to my funeral.
I was surprised at how many people came.
Why should you be surprised?
You were a very well-liked person.
- Yeah. I was, wasn't I?
- Well, I liked you.
Debbie Klein cried a lot.
Oh, God. Am I asleep now or what?
So... So you know what she does?
She's so grief-stricken, she runs
to find solace in Mark Levine's bed.
Mark Levine?
An asshole. Life mocks me even in death.
I'm going completely crazy.
- David!
- What?
Now, I'm really sorry to be upsetting you,
but I have to warn you.
- Warn me?
- We were attacked by a werewolf.
- I'm not listening to this.
- On the moors.
We were attacked by a lycanthrope,
a werewolf.
I was murdered. An unnatural death.
And now I walk the Earth in limbo
until the werewolf's curse is lifted.
- Shut up.
- The wolf's bloodline must be severed.
The last remaining werewolf
must be destroyed.
It's you, David.
- What?
- Please believe me.
You'll kill people.
- Nurse!
- Listen to me!
Nurse!
The supernatural, the power of darkness,
it's all true.
The undead surround me.
Have you ever talked to a corpse?
It's boring.
I'm lonely.
Take your life, David.
Kill yourself before you kill others.
Please don't cry.
Beware the moon, David.
David. David!
David, what's wrong?
I'm a werewolf.
A werewolf?
Are you all right now?
I don't know.
I'll let you know the next full moon.
David, you're going to be discharged
tomorrow. Will you be all right?
My friend Jack was just here.
- Your dead friend Jack?
- Yes.
He told me that
I will become a monster in two days.
What do you think?
What do I think?
About the possibility of you becoming
a monster in two days
or about visits from dead friends?
I was dreaming again?
Yes, I would think so.
I think so, too.
Do you have somewhere to stay in London?
Remember, I'm just a working girl.
So don't expect too much.
- Do you live by yourself?
- Yes.
Good.
There's a shop on the corner.
We'll get some food.
This stuff's expensive.
It's outrageous. My pay can't
possibly keep up with inflation.
How do you live?
Carefully.
This is the living room.
You mind if I get rid of this?
- Oh, please.
- Thank you.
- The kitchen.
- Very nice.
- Closet.
- Charming.
- The bathroom.
- Lovely.
The bedroom.
There's only one bed.
I'll be perfectly honest with you, David.
I'm not in the habit of bringing home stray,
young American men.
I should hope not.
I find you very attractive
and a little bit sad.
Go on.
I've had seven lovers in my life,
three of which were one-night stands.
I don't know what I'm trying to say.
Perhaps you'd like to watch telly
whilst I take a shower.
Well, it's a marvelous night for a moondance
With the stars up above in your eyes
A fantabulous night to make romance
Beneath the cover of October skies
And all the leaves on the trees are falling
To the sound of the breezes that blow
And I'm trying to please to the calling
Of your heartstrings that play soft and low
And all the night's magic
seems to whisper and hush
And all the soft moonlight seems to shine
In your blush
Can I just have
one more moondance with you
My love
Can I just make some more romance with you
You're not real.
Don't be a putz, David.
Come here.
A nurse, huh?
Come on.
What are you doing here?
I wanted to see you.
- Hi, David.
- Put that down.
Okay, you've seen me. Now go away.
I'm sorry I'm upsetting you, David,
but you don't understand what's going on.
I understand, all right.
You're one of the "undead,"
and I'm a werewolf.
Yes. That's right.
Get out of here, Jack.
Tomorrow night's the full moon.
You're gonna change. You'll become...
I know. I know. A monster.
You gotta kill yourself, David,
before it's too late.
Are you really dead, Jack?
What do you think?
I think I've lost my mind.
I think you're not real. I think
you're just another part of a bad dream.
You gotta believe me, David.
Believe what?
That tomorrow night beneath the full moon
I'll sprout hair and fangs and eat people?
- Bullshit!
- Oh, God damn it, David, please believe me.
You'll kill and make others like me.
I'm not having a nice time here.
You gotta take your own life.
I will not accept this. Go away.
David?
This is not pretend, David.
I will not be threatened
by a walking meat loaf!
David.
What's wrong? I heard voices.
It was just me, Alex. Just me being crazy.
Are you all right?
No, I don't think so.
Come back to bed now.
Do I seem crazy to you?
David, what is the matter?
I just saw Jack again.
Where? Here?
Yeah.
What did he say?
He said that tomorrow
I'll turn into a monster.
Do you believe him?
Do you believe me?
I believe that you're very upset.
I believe that you loved him very much
and that somehow you blame yourself
for his death.
Did you ever see The Wolf Man?
- Is that the one with Oliver Reed?
- No, the old one.
I don't think so.
Bela Lugosi bites Lon Chaney, Jr.,
and he turns into a werewolf.
- Why are you telling me this?
- No, listen.
Claude Rains is Lon Chaney's father,
and he ends up killing him.
So?
Well, I think that a werewolf can only
be killed by someone who loves him.
What are you talking about?
I don't know what I'm talking about.
I'm torn between feeling very sorry for you
and finding you terribly attractive.
A drink for a very cold man.
Good afternoon. What can I get you?
- A Campari soda would do very nice, I think.
- Sorry, love.
Oh, well, then a small Guinness will suffice.
Nasty business with those two
young American boys, wasn't it?
- I don't know what you mean, sir.
- Yes, I'm sure I'm right.
A few weeks back. Last full moon, wasn't it?
I mean, the escaped lunatic,
the one who killed the boy.
A thousand thanks, madam. There we are.
Well, that was around here, wasn't it?
Where are you from, sir?
London.
Excuse me.
Knight takes pawn?
What?
Oh, yeah.
Cheers.
- Oh, what's that?
- Oh, that's been there for 200 years, sir.
We were going to paint it out,
but it's traditional, so we left it.
I see.
So, you've heard nothing of this incident?
- Incident?
- The murder.
- You a police officer?
- Oh, good Lord, no, no.
No, I'm a doctor. I work in the hospital
where they brought the Kessler boy.
He was talking about werewolves. Monsters.
I happened to be in the area, so I thought...
You thought what?
I thought I'd look into the boy's story.
Story about werewolves?
Really, sir.
Like a game?
- Well?
- I think not.
Surely I'm not that impressive.
No. No, sir, you're not.
I don't feel like a game.
- You off now?
- Aye. I'll not be long.
I just wanna check on the dogs.
The dogs are fine.
I'll just check.
Quite a long drive to London.
Do you have anything to eat?
No. There's no food here.
There's nothing for you here, sir.
Well,
I'll be on my way, then.
Hello.
Now, listen. That boy's in danger.
I mean,
it were a mistake to let him leave here.
There's something wrong with this place.
That much I understand.
It's the one who lived.
He's the one who's in danger,
and not just him.
Others will be, too.
It's almost full moon.
He'll change, and he'll...
That's enough!
That's enough.
If you get too anxious,
call me at the hospital, okay?
Okay.
- I've left those pills for you.
- A doper werewolf.
I'm off.
See you later.
Thanks a lot, dog.
Hello.
Snarl!
...lost 28 pounds
in less than a fortnight.
Rab Smith, neat, dapper little character.
There's a lot said about big,
gross darts players, but Rab...
Crazy girl asked me to meet her guy
before she married him...
In the News of the World tomorrow.
...and he totally blew my mind.
Nina Carter reveals her amazing life
as pop star, beauty queen and top model.
Read about her nude pictures.
The only ones I regret were among the first.
The men in her life.
There may have been a lot,
but I don't regret one of them.
Nina tells the News of the World
how she had fun
and found trouble earning too much money,
getting in too much mischief.
In the end, it nearly destroyed me.
Don't miss the naked truth
about Naughty Nina,
starting in the News of the World tomorrow.
I see the bad moon rising
I see trouble on the way
I see earthquakes and lightning
I see bad times today
Don't go around tonight
Well, it's bound to take your life
There's a bad moon on the rise
I'm not hungry.
I hear hurricanes a-blowing
I know the end is coming soon
I feel rivers overflowing
I hear the voice of rage and ruin
Don't go around tonight
Well, it's bound to take your life
There's a bad moon on the rise
All right
Fe-fi-fo-fum,
I smell the blood of an Englishman.
I'm still not hungry.
Hope you got your things together
Hope you are quite prepared to die
Looks like we're in for nasty weather
One eye is taken for an eye
Well, don't go round tonight
Well, it's bound to take your life
- How are we feeling tonight?
- No!
- No what?
Benjamin, have you ever been
severely beaten about the face and neck?
- No!
- I thought not.
Now, go to sleep. Sweet dreams...
- No!
No.
Blue moon
You saw me standing alone
Jesus Christ!
Without a dream in my heart
What?
God! What?
Without a love of my own
Oh! Oh! I'm burning up!
Blue moon
You knew just what I was there for
God!
You heard me saying a prayer for
Someone I really could care for
Then suddenly there appeared before me
The only one my arms could ever hold
Then I heard somebody whisper
Please adore me
When I looked the moon had turned to gold
Oh, help me!
Blue moon
Please, help me!
Help me!
Now I'm no longer alone
Without a dream in my, my, my, my heart
I didn't mean to call you a meat loaf, Jack!
Without a love of my own
Blue, blue, blue, blue moon
You saw me standing alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love, without a love
without a love
Of my own
Blue moon
You knew just what I was there for
You heard me saying a prayer for
Someone I really could care for
Then suddenly there appeared before me
The only one my arms could ever hold
Then I heard somebody whisper
Please adore me
And when I looked
the moon had turned to gold
Blue moon
Now I'm no longer alone
Without a dream in my, my, my, my heart
Without a love of my, my, my, my own
Without a love
That's 1.50, please.
- Thank you.
- Night.
- Which one, Harry?
- Number 39.
- Hey, let's go round the back.
- Why?
Come on. We'll give Sean a scare.
- It's freezing cold!
- Oh, come on.
You're crazy, Harry.
What are we doing?
We're going to creep up round
the stairs and give him a ripe old scare.
- Hey, did you hear something?
- Just now?
- Yes.
- No.
Sean, those hooligans are in the park again.
Aren't you ready yet?
They'll be here any minute.
There's something going on out there.
- Is Nurse Price on duty this evening?
- Yes, Doctor.
Nurse Gallagher, do you know if Nurse Price
has seen the Kessler boy since his release?
I don't know.
Yes, Doctor. I have.
Come to my office, Nurse Price.
Is anyone there?
Sit down, Alex.
I was in East Proctor today.
- I'm concerned about David.
- Yes, sir.
There's a full moon. Where is he?
- He's at my flat.
- What's the number?
- I'm off at midnight, and...
- Your number.
Is that you, Harry?
- No, he's not there.
- He's not?
Alex,
has David persisted
in his werewolf fantasies?
Dr. Hirsch, what's wrong?
Is this more serious than I know?
I tried to investigate the attack.
There are no records.
Case was closed.
Now they've "misplaced" the file.
David's lacerations were cleaned
and dressed before he arrived here.
Yet supposedly,
no other doctor examined him before I did.
The Goodman boy's in the ground already.
He's no use to us.
So, I went to the pub in East Proctor today,
where I was convinced of two things.
They were lying. There were no witnesses,
no escaped lunatic.
The whole community is hiding the truth
of what actually happened up there.
Surely, you don't mean...
David has suffered a severe trauma.
I myself witnessed some form of
mass neurosis in East Proctor.
If all the villagers believe that
Jack Goodman was killed by a werewolf,
why shouldn't David?
And then it follows
that if he survived an attack by a werewolf,
wouldn't he himself become a werewolf
at the next full moon?
Oh, I don't mean running about on all fours
and howling at the moon,
but in such a deranged state he might harm
himself or perhaps other people.
- What shall we do?
- I think we should call the police.
Here. Old Winston smells something.
- Let him go!
- Hey! Find what it is.
- That's it.
- Brave dog, that.
Here! Who's there?
That's not Winston.
Look. There!
What's...
Mary, mother of God!
Hello?
Is there someone there?
I can assure you
this is not in the least bit amusing.
I shall report this.
Good Lord.
Hello, wolves. Nice wolves.
I'm gonna... I'll be right back, okay?
Just take any calls.
Oh, boy.
No, Dr. Hirsch. He hasn't come back yet.
Yes, I will.
But I feel so helpless
just sitting around here doing nothing.
Yes, thank you.
Goodbye.
Excuse me.
Hey, kid!
Little boy with the balloons!
Come over here!
If you come over here, I'll give you a pound.
Two pounds.
I don't know who you are.
I'm the famous balloon thief.
Why would a thief want to give me
two pounds?
Here, I'll explain it to you.
Thank you.
Yes, love?
- A naked American man stole my balloons.
- What?
Twenty pence, please, sir.
Sorry.
Lot of weather we've been having lately.
Good morning!
- I'm freezing.
- David!
Where on earth have you been?
Alex, you won't believe this.
I've lost my mind. I woke up in the zoo.
- The zoo.
- What did I do last night?
You don't remember?
Well, I remember seeing you to the door,
and then
saying goodbye,
getting locked out of the flat.
Then I came in through the front window.
I started to read,
and then I woke up naked at the zoo.
I was worried about you.
We didn't know where you were.
Oh!
Where did you get that coat?
I'll get it.
- Hello?
- Alex, have you heard anything?
He's here.
Is he all right? Why didn't you call me?
Where was he?
He doesn't remember.
He woke up at the zoo.
The zoo? Is he rational?
Yes, he is. He's very excited and confused.
But he's not crazy, if that's what you mean.
Have you read the papers today?
Or listened to the radio or the television?
- No. Why?
- Is David behaving strangely?
No, he's not really.
He's rather enthusiastic.
- Could you get here without any trouble?
- Yes, I should think so.
I want you to bring David here straightaway.
I want him in my care.
I'll notify the police that we've found him.
But it's imperative you bring him
straight to the hospital. You understand?
Yes, Doctor.
Now, you're certain he's lucid?
You won't need any help?
No, he's fine. We'll come right over.
- Shall I send a car?
- A taxi will be faster.
I expect you shortly.
- We should be able to get a taxi here.
- You know, I should be committed.
Here we are.
Dr. Hirsch will know what to do.
I don't know why I feel so good.
I haven't felt this good in a long time.
My body feels great. I feel like an athlete.
Let's go back to your place
for a quickie, huh?
- Later.
- Oh, come on. Later, okay.
- Good morning!
- Get in.
I just...
- St. Martin's Hospital.
- Right.
It puts you in mind of the days of the
old Demon Barber of Fleet Street, doesn't it?
- Sorry?
- The murders.
- What murders?
- Haven't you heard?
Last night,
six of them.
All in different parts of the city,
all mutilated.
He must be a real right maniac, this fella.
- Pull over. Pull over!
- David, we're going to the...
- Pay the man.
- We must get...
Wait!
David!
- David, stop!
- I'm going to the police!
- Jack was right!
- Jack is dead!
Jack is dead. And six people are dead.
There's gonna be a full moon tonight.
I'm going to the cops.
David, please be rational.
Let's go to Dr. Hirsch.
Be rational, sure.
I'm a fucking werewolf, for Christ's sake!
- David!
- Officer!
Officer, I killed those people last night.
- You did, did you?
- He's playing a silly joke, Officer...
- You be quiet.
- We had an argument.
- I don't know this girl.
- All right, you two. Move along, then.
Come on. David...
Come on.
I want you to arrest me, you asshole!
There's no call for that kind of language.
Queen Elizabeth is a man!
Prince Charles is a faggot!
- Winston Churchill was full of shit!
- That's enough.
- No! Let go of me!
- David, please!
Shakespeare's French! Fuck! Shit!
Cunt! Shit!
- Come on. That's enough.
- David, please!
Who is this person?
If you don't stop this disturbance,
I shall arrest you.
That's what I want you to do, you moron!
- He's very upset. His friend was killed.
- Will you shut up?
That's quite enough.
About your business, both of you. Come on.
You're not gonna arrest me?
- Don't you think he should arrest me?
- I don't know.
- Perhaps he thinks it's a prank.
- A prank?
- David...
- Look, I've had enough of this foolishness.
All right, come on. There's nothing to see.
- It's hopeless. It's hopeless.
- Let's go.
Leave me alone! You people are crazy!
- I gotta get out of here!
- David, don't lose control!
Control! What control?
Jack was real. He tried to warn me,
and I thought I was crazy.
- David...
- I love you.
- What?
But I think I did some terrible things
last night, things I can't remember.
- David, let's go see Dr. Hirsch.
- No, you gotta stay away from me.
- David, I can help you.
- No, I'm not safe to be with.
You gotta stay away from me.
I love you, Alex.
David!
The forensic lab seemed to feel that some
sort of animal was involved, that's true.
- I hardly think it could be...
- Regardless of what you think, Inspector,
the fact remains that David is missing,
and we must find him.
- Before nightfall.
- Precisely.
Gentlemen, please.
We shall find Mr. Kessler
as quickly as we're able.
He tried to get himself arrested.
Getting arrested isn't all that difficult,
Miss Price.
He wants help. He really...
- How can we assist you?
- Stay here.
If we need you,
we'll know where to reach you.
I cannot accept a connection between
David Kessler and last night's murders.
We will find him, however.
I can assure you of that.
We'll find him. Not to worry.
I promise.
Yes, operator, I'd like to call
the United States and reverse the charges.
David Kessler, for anyone.
Thank you. I'll wait.
Hello? It's area code 516,
472-3402.
402.
Thank you.
Hello, Rachel?
Just say yes, you'll accept the charges.
Say yes, Rachel.
Hi. Is Mom or Dad at home?
Well, where are they?
Well, where's Max?
You're all alone?
Mom and Dad would never leave me alone
when I was 10.
No, not 10-and-a-half, either.
I'm still in London. Yes, I'm all better now.
Listen, Rachel,
tell Mom and Dad that I love them, okay?
Just do it for me, will you, please?
And
don't fight with Max.
Yeah, well, try.
And please don't forget what I told you
about Mom and Dad.
That I love them.
And I love Max, and I love you, too.
No, I do.
No, I'm not being silly, you little creep.
You promise?
Okay.
You be a good girl, then.
Yeah, I love you.
Goodbye.
- How much is it?
- £2.80, sir.
Hi, Jack.
Hi, David.
What are you doing here?
You promised never to do
this kind of thing again.
- I never promised you any such thing.
- Not you, you twit. Her.
- I've never seen you before in my life.
- Oh, sorry.
Good movie.
Mmm-hmm.
What can I say, Jack?
You don't have to say anything, David.
Aren't you gonna say "I told you so"?
If I were still alive, I probably would.
But I did tell you so, you schmuck.
- You look awful.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it.
I don't know what I'm saying.
I don't even know if it was me
that killed those people last night.
I don't remember doing it.
What about the zoo?
Well, even if I'm not the Wolf Man,
I'm crazy enough to do something like that.
Look at me. Here I sit in a porno theater
in Piccadilly Circus
talking to a corpse.
I'm actually glad to see you, Jack.
I want you to meet some people.
David Kessler, this is Gerald Bringsley.
Gerald's the man you murdered
on the subway.
We thought it best for you not to see him,
as he's a fresh kill and still pretty messy.
Yes. I do look most unpleasant.
Why are you doing this to me?
This isn't Mr. Goodman's idea.
He's your good friend,
whereas I am a victim
of your carnivorous lunar activities.
Mr. Bringsley, I'm sorry.
I have absolutely no idea what to say to you.
You've left my wife a widow
and my children fatherless.
And, I understand, I am to walk
the Earth in limbo, one of the living dead,
until the wolf's bloodline is severed
and the curse lifted.
You must die, David Kessler.
David?
This is Harry Berman and his fiancée,
Judith Browns.
- Hello.
And these gentlemen are
Alf, Ted and Joseph.
Can't say we're pleased to meet you,
Mr. Kessler.
What shall I do?
- Suicide.
- You must take your own life.
That's easy for you to say.
You're already dead.
No, David. Harry and I and everyone
you murdered are not dead, the undead.
Why are you doing this to me?
Because this must be stopped.
How shall I do it?
- Sleeping pills?
- Not sure enough.
- I could hang myself.
- No.
No, if you did it wrong, it could be painful.
You'd choke to death.
- So what? Let him choke!
- Do you mind? The man's a friend of mine!
- Well, he ain't no friend to me.
- Gentlemen, please.
- A gun!
- I know where you can get a gun.
- Don't I need a silver bullet or something?
- Oh, be serious, would you?
- Madness.
- No, a gun would be good.
Yes. Just put the gun to your forehead
and pull the trigger.
But if you put it in your mouth,
you'd be sure not to miss.
- Thank you. You're all so thoughtful.
- A knife!
- An electric shock!
- A car crash?
- You could throw yourself in front of a tube.
- Drowning.
Don't stop!
Go away.
Please, go away.
Please, run!
What was that?
- I don't know!
- I'll check on the house.
Hello?
No, I'm sorry.
No, nobody of that name.
Okay. Thank you. Bye.
Help! Help!
- Help!
- What's the matter?
- There's a mad thing in there!
- Where?
- A mad dog is tearing...
- Calm down!
- Oh, do something!
- Quit shouting!
Oh, right there. Yeah, right there.
Oh, yeah, harder. Oh, yeah.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, here he is.
For Christ's sake, John,
there's a monster in there!
Call for assistance!
Tell them to bring rifles!
Will you people get out of the way!
- What the hell's going on here?
- Some kind of animal, sir.
Sister Hobbs said there's a disturbance
in Piccadilly Circus
involving some sort of mad dog.
David!
It's a dead end down there!
Clear this street off!
David. It's David.
Alex. Alex!
- Let me through!
- Stand aside, miss!
You must let me through!
- Come back!
- Alex!
David? Is it you?
David.
They're going to kill you.
Please.
Please let me help you.
I love you, David.
Bom-ba-ba-bom-ba ba-bom-ba-ba-bom-ba
ba-bom-ba-ba-bom
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Blue moon, moon, moon
Blue moon
Dip-da-dip-da-dip
Blue, blue, blue, blue moon
Moon, moon, moon, blue moon
Dip-da-dip-da-dip
Bom-ba-ba-bom-ba ba-bom-ba-ba-bom-ba
ba-bom-ba-ba-bom
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Blue moon
You saw me standing alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love of my own
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Blue moon
You knew just what I was there for
You heard me saying a prayer for
Someone I really could care for
And then there suddenly appeared before me
The only one my arms would ever hold
I heard somebody whisper please adore me
And when I looked
the moon had turned to gold
Blue moon
Now I'm no longer alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love of my own
Bom-ba-ba-bom-ba ba-bom-ba-ba-bom-ba
ba-bom-ba-ba-bom
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Blue moon
You saw me standing alone
Without a dream in my heart
Without a love of my own
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Blue moon
You knew just what I was there for
You heard me saying a prayer for
Someone I really could care for
And then there suddenly appeared before me
The only one my arms would ever hold
I heard somebody whisper please adore me
And when I looked
the moon had turned to gold
Blue moon
Now I'm no longer alone
Without a dream in my heart
Bom-ba-ba-bom-ba ba-bom-ba-ba-bom-ba
ba-bom-ba-ba-bom
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Dip-da-dip-da-dip
Bom-ba-ba-bom-ba ba-bom-ba-ba-bom-ba
ba-bom-ba-ba-bom
A-dang-a-dang-dang a-ding-a-dong-ding
Blue moon